Finding Aid for Barbour Scholarship for Oriental Women Committee (University of Michigan) records, 1914-1983
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Barbour Scholarship for Oriental Women Committee (University of Michigan)records 1914-1983
University of Michigan. Barbour Scholarship for Oriental Women Committee.
1 linear foot and 3 folders
861142 UBImum BImu B17 2
Records, 1914-1983, of the Barbour Scholarship for Oriental Women Committee, founded by University of Michigan alumnus and regent Levi L. Barbour. Include minutes (1918-1946), complete lists of recipients (1914-1983), newsletters (1927-1946), photographs, and correspondence (1918-1983).
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material vas received from the Barbour Scholarship Committee in 1972 and 1983 (donor no. 5223 ). Supplemental materials have been transferred to this collection from other university collections.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Barbour Scholarship for Oriental Women was created through the generosity of Levi L. Barbour. Barbour was a graduate of the University of Michigan (1863) and the Michigan Law School (1865) who went on to become a successful Detroit real estate developer. Barbour served as a regent of the University from 1892-1898 and again from 1902-1908.
As a result of personal observations of the work of three Oriental women trained at Michigan, Barbour became committed to a program of bringing Oriental women to the University of Michigan, where they could receive formal education which would be of benefit to both themselves and their native land. The first Barbour scholars arrived in 1914, and the program became permanent in 1917 through a gift of $50,000 by Barbour to the University. Barbour subsequently increased the sum of the endowment several times. According to the terms of the gift, a committee, composed of the University's president, the dean of the College of Literature, Science and the Arts, the dean of the Medical School and the Dean of Women, was to choose the scholars and administer the program.
The records of the Barbour Scholarship Committee comprise minutes (1918-1946), complete lists of recipients (1914-1983), newsletters (1927-1946), and photos and correspondence (1918-1983). The collection measures less than one linear foot. Photos include yearly group photographs of recipients, photographs of informal parties, and portraits of Levi L. Barbour and others.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Students.; University of Michigan--Students--Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Students, Foreign--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Barbour, Levi L. (Levi Lewis), 1840-1925.; University of Michigan. Barbour Scholarships for Oriental Women Committee.; University of Michigan--Students.; Women.; Students, Foreign--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Records
  - History (Box 1)
  - Recipients, 1914-1983 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1918-1946 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1918-1983 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1927-1946 (Box 1)
  - Printed (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Medallion (artifacts) (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Levi Barbour and Scholarship Committee (Box 1)
  - Frank Huntley and Mrs. Huntley with Barbour Scholars (Box 1)
  - Barbour Scholars (Box 1)
    (informal shots and parties)
  - Recipients, 1924-1950, 3 outsize folders (Folder UBImum B17)